接下来我们要做的是 12 号
So the next thing we're
gonna do node-12-stretch.
这将作为容器的 root 用户运行。
This is running as the root
user of the container.
通常，不要以 root用户身份运行。
In general, don't run things as root.
我的意思是，我认为这对一般来说是一件好事
I mean, I think that's kind of a good
thing in general just to learn [LAUGH] for
系统安全之类的东西
system security and stuff like that.
如果有人接管你的电脑就像 root 用户一样
If someone takes over your computer and
it's being ran as the root user,
然后他们就可以为所欲为了
then they can just do whatever
they want to your computer.
所以这才是最不权力的原则。
So that's kind of the principle
of least power right.
因此，您要创建一个用户，使该用户能够执行服务器和
So you wanna create a user that all
that user can do is run your server and
什么都能做对吧
can do nothing else, right?
所以如果有人最终结束你的容器
So if someone does eventually end
up taking over your container,
他们只能做自己可以做的事情。
they can only do things that
that user is allowed to do.
他们做不到 root 的事情吧 ?
They can't do root things right?
如果您不熟悉 Linux中使用的路径，
If you're not familiar with
what route uses to in Linux,
这也会把一切都策划好了
again, this will plot
everything out there, so
可能是工作但他们是那个集装箱的神对吧
it's probably work, but
they're the god of that container, right?
这就是重点
That's the gist.
所以我们可以在这里做些什么
So something we could do here
我们可以说用户节点
is we could say user, Node.
节点容器随附的一个凉爽的东西就是它有
One of the cool things that the node
container ships with is that it has
一个叫做节点的用户，专门为此目的建立的。
another user on it called node, that's
build specifically for this purpose.
但知道这里没有什么特殊的东西叫做节点
But know that there's nothing
special that this is called node and
这称为节点。
this is called node.
是这个容器的创造者创建了一个叫节点的用户
It's the creators of this container
created a user called node and
用户组中的用户称为 " 节点 " 以进行混淆。
that you that users in a user group
called node to look confusing.
但我可以说，如果我开始像 Ruby 容器那样运行，对吗 ?
But suffice to say, like, if I start
running like a Ruby container, right?
这方面不一定是 Ruby 用户。
There won't necessarily
be a Ruby user on that.
我不想再联系你了
I don't want that connection
to click in your head.
这就是我想说的
That's all I'm trying to say.
所以现在我觉得这个应该是可以的。
So now, I think this should work.
这将作为节点用户执行。
And this would be
executing as the node user.
但任何时候我们都是这样复制的
But any time that we run copy like this,
这仍然会将其复制为 root 用户。
this is still going to
copy it as the root user.
这意味着此用户无权修改或执行
Which means that this user has no
permission to modify or execute or
都是些什么东西
any of that kind of stuff.
所以我们必须要运行它。
So we do have to run it.
我先把这两个都换好，让用户节点先到这里来。
I'm gonna switch those two first of all so
that user node comes up here first.
所以我们要做破折号的破折号，幸运的 VS 代码，它把我的背带回来了。
And so we have to do dash dash, and
luckily VS code, it's got my back.
所以你可以做 CHOWN ，也可以做 FROM ，我要做 CHOWN。
So you can either do CHOWN or
you can do FROM and I'm gonna do CHOWN.
您必须考虑用户和组。
And you have to think about the user and
the group.
所以我要说节点:节点，因为用户的名称是节点，
So I'm gonna say node:node because
the name of the user is node,
该组的名称为节点。
the name of the group is node.
现在，正在复制它，并且将由该用户节点来进行电话。
And so now, this is being copied over and
it will be phoned by this user node.
我不知道为什么这是我在做的事
I don't know why this is,
it's cuz I was doing that.
好了好了
There we go.
好的。
Okay.
现在，如果我再次运行，或者 Docker 运行，
So now if I do this run again,
or Docker run,
建造，建造，就在那里
build, build, there we go that one.
一切都好
Everything's all good to go.
它正在建立一个新的用户节点。
It's putting a new user node.
来看看这个
Check this out.
所以如果我再做一次我说我是谁
So if I run it again And I say who am I?
它会说现在的节点对吧
It's gonna say now node, right?
所以它作为一个节点用户被执行。
So it's being executed as a node user.
但我想证明我的意思是如果我回到这里
But just to kind of like prove my
point to if I come back over here and
我对这条线说对了，我再做一次。
I comment this line out right,
and I build it again.
我说你期待他说 " 根 " 是谁
And I say who am I when you
expect him to say root right?
缺省情况下您是 root 用户吗 ?
You're the root user by default?
>> 因此，用户名的发现过程与此过程有关，
&gt;&gt; So the user name what's
the discover process on that with,
会有检查吗
will there be the inspect?
命令?
Command?
>> 你可以的，你肯定可以通过检查发现的。
&gt;&gt; You could, yeah, you can
definitely find out through inspect.
我可能就像 Docker Hub上的文档一样。
I probably just find that through like
the documentation on the Docker Hub.
换句话说，没有真正的方法去发现它。
Or in other words, there's not really
a specific way of finding that out.
说实话我可能只是照我说的做才行我是谁
Honestly, I probably just do what I
showed you which is just run, who am I?
>> Gotcha。
&gt;&gt; Gotcha.
稍后，我将向您展示如何创建用户。
Later in the course I'll show you
actually how to create users.
例如，如果您直接从 Ubuntu 中运行它，
For example, if you're running
it directly out of Ubuntu,
他们没有为您创建的任何用户，所以您必须自己做。
they don't have any users created for
you, so you have to do it yourself.
这不是很困难，基本上是一个命令。
It's not very hard,
it's basically one command.
我永远记不起来了，所以我一直都是谷歌。
And I can never remember it,
so I always Google it.
好的，请快速说明副本。
[LAUGH] Okay, so quick note on copy.
这里还有一个人被人搞糊涂了
There is another command here,
which people get confused with, and
我只是想解决这个问题
I just wanted to address that.
还有一个叫做 ADD
There's another one, called ADD.
如果我这样做，你也可以做 CHON 。
And if I did this,
you can do the CHON as well with that.
这也行吧
This would also work, right?
实际上在这个时刻
And actually, At this moment in time,
第 7 行和第 5 行都做同样的事
these things do, line seven and
line five do exactly the same thing.
因此， ADD 有一些类似的额外功能。
So ADD has some like extra
functionality associated with it.
它会为本地文件系统工作。
It does work for your local file system.
我想说如果你在做我们正在做的事情
I would say if you're doing stuff like
what we're doing right here which just is
本地文件系统。
the local file system.
用副本上更安全
Use copy, it's safer.
少了，一般少做比较好
It does less, and doing less in
general is a better thing for
你要是做了你需要做的事情
you if it does the thing
that you need it to do.
但是， ADD 的伟大方法是 ADD 可以进入网络，
However, what's great about ADD
is ADD can go out to the network,
它可以从网络中下载一个文件，对吧 ?
it can download a file off the network,
right?
所以如果我说的是 GitHub.com 这个特定的文件，
So if I say add from GitHub.com
this particular file,
它就会出来，下载档案，吐出来。
it will go out, download the file,
spit it out there.
这就是 ADD 将为你做的一件事。
So that's one thing that ADD will do for
you.
此外， ADD 还会自动解压缩并使用它，对吗 ?
And ADD will also automatically unzip and
use it that it gets, right?
所以如果你是焦油，对。
So if you are a tar, right.
因此，如果我说添加这一焦油，它会立即下载并将其解压缩。
So if I say add this tar, it'll
download it and unzip it immediately.
如果我复印了我就得进去
Whereas if I had done copy,
I'd have to go in there and
马上就能跑出来了
do a run immediately after that.
因此，如果您正在网络中执行任何操作，或者您需要在 zip 上执行任何操作，请使用 ADD。
So if you're doing anything in the network
or you need anything on ziip, use ADD.
其他所有使用副本的 100 % 。
For 100% of everything else use copy.
我们不使用，我不认为我们用 ADD for
We won't be using,
I don't think we use ADD for
其他的课但你知道它在外面是好事
the rest of the class but it's good for
you to know that it's out there.
所以我想做的就是，将这个 index.js 复制到哪里 ?
So the next thing I wanna do is,
where's this index.js being copied?
项目的根目录，不是非常组织的。
The root directory of the project,
not very organized.
所以我不会建议你这么做
So I'm not gonna suggest that you do that.
所以我们要在这个问题上加上一个指令，然后说 " WORKDIR" 。
So we're gonna add a command
right about this and say WORKDIR.
我们要把这个放在家里
And we're gonna put this on home node,
right ，是节点用户的主目录。
right, which is the home
directory of the node user.
然后我就在这个叫代码的飞行上创建一个，对吧 ?
And then I'm gonna just create one
on the fly called code, right?
我要把所有的密码都放进去
I'm gonna put all my code and
so home/node/code.
人们把它放进密码里的人把它放在了源头上
People put it in code
people put it in source.
事实上，源极可能更常见。
Actually source is probably more common.
但我要用我的笔记上的代码说只要有好的地方
But I am gonna take the code that is on my
notes, say, just wherever it is good to
把它放在像家里的目录里之类的
put it inside of like the home
directory or something like that.
因为我们知道节点用户拥有自己的主目录。
Because we know for sure the node
user owns its own home directory.
这很不错
It is good.
很不错的地方
Good place to put it.
为了证明这一点
So to prove a point here.
我要说 pwd 和这个会告诉你我正被砍了对吗
I'm gonna say pwd and
this will tell you, I'm in slash, right?
所以我就在这个斜杠的目录里，但是它不是以前的，
So I'm in the slash directory,
but it wasn't before and
现在如果我重新开始建造码头
now if I run docker build again And
我再次运行它，现在您可以看到它在主节点代码中。
I run this again,
you can see now it's in home node code.
因此，这意味着所有在此之后的命令都将基于此目录，对吗 ?
So that means all commands after that
will be based in this directory, right?
所以这就是你的工作目录
So that's where your working
directory Hence, WORKDIR,
我想是描述性的
it's descriptive I suppose.
同样，对于 WORKDIR ，如果它不存在，
And again, nice thing about WORKDIR,
if it doesn't exist,
它会为你创造的
it will just create it for you.